Guide to the RIDGE Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- RIDGE/SUNCADIA LITIGATION, 1923, 1988-2013; 1988-2013; SERIES 6 (Box-folder 2/25-28, 2/36, 3/1, 3/9-22, 4/1-2, 4/23, 5/20, 5/33-34, 6/1-13, 7/1-4, 7/10-15, 8/12, 8/15, 8/18-20, 8/24-28, 8/38-40, 10, Tube 4)
  - Settlement Drafts, Agreements, Amendments, and Easements, 1991-2010; bulk 2000-2010; Subseries C (Box-folder 3/9-13, 3/15-22, 4/1-2, 5/33-34, 6/11-13, 7/1-4, 8/19-20, 10)
    - Cooperative Agreement (2 of 2), 2003 April 1-2004 December (Box-folder 3/13)
      Contains oversize enlargements
    - MountainStar and Stream C Draft Land Stewardship Plans and Cooperative Agreement between Washington Department of Fish and Wildlife, Yakama Nation, and Trendwest Resorts, Inc., 2003 January-2005 November (Box-folder 3/15)
    - Mountainstar Land Stewardship Plan and Stream "C" Addendum Reports (1 of 2), 2003 July 15-2006 August 25 (Box-folder 3/16)
      Contains CD-rom
    - Mountainstar Land Stewardship Plan and Stream "C" Addendum Reports (2 of 2), 2003 July 15-2006 August 25 (Box-folder 3/17)
    - CD 22: Roslyn Land Stewardship Plan, Prepared by James Begley of Central Washington University, 2007 May 18 (Box 10)
    - Trendwest Resorts, Inc. and RIDGE Agreement (1 of 2), 2006 June 17 (Box-folder 3/18)
    - Trendwest Resorts, Inc. and RIDGE Agreement (2 of 2), 2006 June 17 (Box-folder 3/19)
    - First Amendment to Phase 3 Managed Open Space Conservation Easement, 2006 June 21 (Box-folder 3/20)
    - Stream C Corridor Grant of Conservation Easement, 2006 June 13 (Box-folder 3/21)
    - RIDGE and Washington First Law Center's Mountainwest Settlement and Upper Teanaway Subarea Plan Agreement, approximately 2004-2009 (Box-folder 3/22)
    - Development Resolution for Roslyn, Washington, 2003 March 25 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - RIDGE Settlement Agreement Amendments, Modifications, Dispute Resolutions, and Final Documents, 2002 September 18-2006 May 8 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - RIDGE Settlement Agreement, 1991 January 13-2006 December 21 (Box-folder 5/33)
      Contains oversize maps and blueprints
    - Recorded Easements, 2003 August 20-2006 January 28 (Box-folder 5/34)
    - Signed Trendwest/RIDGE Contract, 2001 April 8-May 15 (Box-folder 6/11)
    - Douglas Kilgore: Implementation of Provision 1.56 (Big Creek) of RIDGE Settlement Agreement, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 6/12)
    - RIDGE Settlement Agreement Amendments and Dispute Resolution Documents (1 of 5), 2002-2010 (Box-folder 6/13)
      Contains CD-roms and oversize map
    - RIDGE Settlement Agreement Amendments and Dispute Resolution Documents (2 of 5), 2002-2010 (Box-folder 7/1)
    - RIDGE Settlement Agreement Amendments and Dispute Resolution Documents (3 of 5), 2002-2010 (Box-folder 7/2)
    - RIDGE Settlement Agreement Amendments and Dispute Resolution Documents (4 of 5), 2002-2010 (Box-folder 7/3)
    - RIDGE Settlement Agreement Amendments and Dispute Resolution Documents (5 of 5), 2002-2010 (Box-folder 7/4)
    - Cooperation Agreement Meeting Minutes, Cle Elum River Site Map, 2000 December 4-2003 July 23 (Box-folder 8/19)
    - Timeline of Second Amendment to RIDGE Settlement Agreement, MountainStar Report, Cle Elum Urban Growth Area, Map, 2002 September 9-2004 May 4 (Box-folder 8/20)
    - CD 1-3: Index and First Amendment, 2005 October 31-2006 November 3 (Box 10)
      contact person listed on exterior of digital files is Maura Woodwell
    - CD 20: Transmittal Memo, Rational, Amended Development Agreement, Amended County Conditions of Approval, Exhibit J and Exhibit M, 2007 August 9-10 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, 1923, 1993-2009; bulk 1993-2009; Subseries D (Box-folder 4/23, 8/12, 8/15, 8/18)
    - Correspondence, Maps, and Land Transfer Documents Related to Trendwest Development, 1923, 1993-1997; 1993-1997 (Box-folder 4/23)
      Contains oversize maps, oversize site plans, and correspondence from Bill Hunt to Douglas Kilgore
    - Road Access, Suncadia Master Planned Resort [MPR] Zoning Correspondence, 2008 August 25-26 (Box-folder 8/12)
    - Suncadia Plans Correspondence, Notes, and Outstanding Issues Dispute Process Documents, 2008 July 21-2009 January 14 (Box-folder 8/15)
    - Correspondence from Douglas Kilgore Concerning Dispute between Suncadia and Cle Elum, Legal Documents Concerning Easement, and Deed of Trust at Plum Creek, 2002 May 5-2009 May 22 (Box-folder 8/18)
  - Negotiation and Proposals, 1988-2007; Subseries E (Box-folder 6/1, 6/3-10, 6/14, 8/38-40, 10)
    - RIDGE Board Member Andy Januzkiewicz's Notes for Negotiations with Trendwest, 1999-2002 (Box-folder 6/1)
    - RIDGE and Trendwest Negotiation (1 of 2), 1997 June 27-2004 March 1 (Box-folder 6/3)
    - RIDGE and Trendwest Negotiation (2 of 2), 1997 June 27-2004 March 1 (Box-folder 6/14)
      Contains oversize meeting wall charts
    - RIDGE Proposals (1 of 3), 2001 June-July (Box-folder 6/4)
    - RIDGE Proposals (2 of 3), 2001 June-July (Box-folder 6/5)
    - RIDGE Proposals (3 of 3), 2001 June-July (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Douglas Kilgore: RIDGE/Trendwest Negotiation (1 of 2), 2001 July-August (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Douglas Kilgore: RIDGE/Trendwest Negotiation (2 of 2), 2001 July-August (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Douglas Kilgore: Trendwest/RIDGE Negotiation File and Final RIDGE Settlement Agreement (1 of 2), 2001 September 9-12 (Box-folder 6/9)
    - Douglas Kilgore: Trendwest/RIDGE Negotiation File and Final RIDGE Settlement Agreement (2 of 2), 2001 September 9-12 (Box-folder 6/10)
    - Miller Property: Proposal Notes and Documents, Proposal by RIDGE to Suncadia, Open Space Analysis, and Traffic Impacts, 2005 April 19-June 1 (Box-folder 8/38)
      Contains oversize maps. The Miller Property was land located adjacent to both the planned Suncadia Resort and Roslyn, Washington. In 2006 and 2007, RIDGE and Suncadia entered into negotiations to add the Miller Property to the resort and to protect large portions of that land in a conservation easement. Suncadia sought to terminate the RIDGE Settlement Agreement, and ultimately succeeded when the Kittitas County Superior Court Judge Scott Sparks terminated the agreement in 2013, voiding the Miller Property conservation easement as well.
    - Miller Property: Notes and CD with Satellite Photographs [?], 1988-2007 March 1 (Box-folder 8/39)
    - Miller Property and Fourth Amendment of Settlement Agreement: Revisions, Correspondence, Notes, Reports, and Maps, 2005 June 1-2007 June 12 (Box-folder 8/40)
      Contains CD-rom and oversize maps
    - CD 9-10: Suncadia Cle Elum River Corridor, Stream C Corridor, Phases 1-3, approximately 2007 (Box 10)
    - CD 11-12: Stream C Land Stewardship Plan, 2005 (Box 10)
  - General Suncadia Files, 1999-2013; Subseries F (Box-folder 2/36, 3/1, 5/20, 6/2, 8/24-28, 10, Tube 4)
    - Suncadia Settlement Agreement Presentation to Kittitas County Court, approximately 2001-2013 (Box-folder 3/1)
      Contains oversize maps and site plans and correspondence from Bill Hunt to Douglas Kilgore.
    - Resource Media Proposal for RIDGE and Suncadia Case Study, approximately 2012 (Box-folder 2/36)
    - Topographical Maps with Notations of Legal Land Boundary Descriptions, 1999 April 22-October 25 (Box-folder 5/20)
      Contains oversize marked topographical map
    - Successorship of Trendwest to MountainStar, 2002 April 17-2004 March 1 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Suncadia Mass Wasting Event, Erosion and Sediment, Correspondence, Notes, Memorandum, and Stormwater Compliance Inspection Report, 2006 November 16-2007 February 28 (Box-folder 8/24)
    - Open Space on Master Planned Resort [MPR] Zoning, Notes on Trails, approximately 2005-2007 (Box-folder 8/25)
    - Draft of Suncadia Resort Golf Course Management Plan, Correspondence, and Notes, 2006 January 1-April 18 (Box-folder 8/26)
    - Suncadia: Notice of Plat Application and Public Hearing, Memorandum from Kittitas County Community Development, Newspaper Clippings, and Correspondence from Ellie Belew, Douglas Kilgore, and Deron Lozano, 2006 March 1-July 13 (Box-folder 8/27)
    - Suncadia Newspaper Clippings, Maps, Correspondence, and Memorandum from Notary Regarding Agreement between TrendWest and RIDGE, 2003 March 3-2006 August 10 (Box-folder 8/28)
      Contains oversize newsprint and map
    - CD 4: Suncadia Site Development Plan Application, Lower River Corridor Paths and Trails, 2007 July 12 (Box 10)
    - CD 8: Suncadia Path and Trail Master Planning Map, 2007 February 16 (Box 10)
    - CD 21: Suncadia Path and Trail Master Planning Map, Dawson Associates, 2008 February 29 (Box 10)
    - Aerial photograph of land SE of Cle Elum Lake: Laminated Photographs Taped Together to form a Large Aerial View of the Land Now Occupied by Suncadia Resort, 1988-2013[?] (Tube Tube 4)
      Restricted until digital version is available.
- AUDIOVISUAL MATERIAL, 1984-2014; SERIES 7 (Box 10)
  Videocassettes on assorted topics related to RIDGE.
  - RIDGE Compliance Study Sessions, 1994 October 19-21 (Video Video 1)
  - RIDGE Yakima Basin Aerial Video, approximately 1984-2014 (Video Video 2)
  - MountainStar Master Planned Resort [MPR] Zoning Site Visit, Judge Susan Hahn and Counsel, 2001 April 12 (Video Video 3)
  - Unmarked VHS, approximately 1995-2005 (Video Video 4)
  - Plum Creek Timber Company, RIDGE Interview, and Town Meeting, approximately 1995-2005 (Video Video 5)
  - Dick Rieman at the High School, approximately 1995-2005 (Video Video 6)
  - Thanksgiving Day, 1989 (Video Video 7)
  - "The West", Show #109, approximately 1984-2014 (Video Video 8)